Nguyen Lam Truong Full-Stack Developer

0328374810 - truongnl032000@gmail.com - Thu Duc, Thành phố Hồ Chí Minh 14/03/2000 - https://portfolio-truongnl.vercel.app/

Summary

Full-Stack Developer with 2 years of experience specializing in Node.js (NestJS), TypeScript, and JavaScript. Strong background in backend development, API optimization, and database performance tuning. Experienced in integrating third-party payment systems (MoMo, VNPay) and working with Docker, Redis, MySQL, and MongoDB. Flexible and adaptable, able to work both independently and collaboratively in a team.

Technical Skills

- Back-End: NodeJS, NestJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Redis, MongoDB, MySQL.
- Front-End: ReactJS, NextJS, React Native, Redux, HTML & CSS.
- DevOps & Tools: Docker, Git.

Other skills: Integrated third-party payment gateways (MoMo, VNPay)

Work Experience

GUVI TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS COMPANY LIMITED | 03/2023 - 08/2024

FullStack Developer

Responsibilities

- Developed and optimized the company's CMS, improving data rendering performance.
- Built and maintained scalable backend services using NestJS, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Integrated third-party payment gateways (MoMo, VNPay) for seamless transactions.
- Optimized API response times using Redis caching reducing latency by 40%.
- Managed version and deployed updates to App Store and Google Play.
- Managed version control and deployed applications using Docker.

Technologies:

NodeJS(NestJS), MongoDB, Redis, Docker, NginX, ReactJS, Firebase

GUVI TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS COMPANY LIMITED | 08/2022 - 03/2023

Fresher Mobile Developer

Responsibilities

- Developed cross-platform mobile applications using React Native.
- Implemented UI components based on Figma designs.
- Integrated APIs to fetch data in mobile apps.
- Debugged and optimized mobile app performance.

Technologies:

React Native, Redux, Redux-saga, Axios, Firebase

Education

FPT Polytechnic College | 08/2022 - 05/2023

Major: Mobile Programming

Languages

English Beginner